(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
3Dバラエティ！あびゃびゃ！全国おいしい発見！
3D Variety! Abyabya! Nationwide Delicious Discoveries!
～高級食材で牛丼づくりに挑む～
~Challenging the Creation of Beef Bowls with High-End Ingredients~
お肉食べようのうた
The Meat-Eating Song
お肉食べよう
Let's eat meat
おニクニクニクニク肉食べたい
Meat-meat-meat-meat, I want to eat meat!
お肉 お肉 お肉
Meat, meat, meat,
お肉食べよう
let's eat meat.
元気 お肉 お肉
Energetic meat, meat,
ほっぺたウルウル
my cheeks are moist.
ウルウルウルウル
Moist, moist, moist...
お肉 お肉 お肉
Meat, meat, meat,
お肉食べよう
let's eat meat.
まんまるおだんご まんまるおだんご
Round dumplings, round dumplings,
かわいい仲間
my cute companions.
タレタレタレ好き
Sauce, sauce, I love sauce!
煮ても
Whether boiled,
焼いても
grilled,
揚げても
or fried,
あなた好み
I'll become just
になるのよ
the way you like.
お鍋
Hot pot,
おべんと パーティー
bento, or a party.
今日は何？何？
What's for today? What?
何？何？何？何！
What? What? What? What!
肉と肉とで肉だんご
Meat and meat make a meatball.
オー肉
Oh, meat!
ニクニク肉
Meat, meat, meat!
オー肉
Oh, meat!
ニクニク肉
Meat, meat, meat!
みんなシアワセ
Everyone is happy.
肉でニコリ
Smiling with meat.
世界が
The world
笑顔いっぱいに
will be full of smiles.
サンキュー
Thank you,
お肉
meat.
ありがとう～！
Thank you~!
お肉じゃぽねすく！
Oniku Japonesque!
国産のお肉
Domestic meat,
domestic meat.
にっくにく じゃぽねすく
Meat-y Japonesque!
飛んできて
Fly over to me,
とりあえずギュウってしててば
and for now, just give me a 'gyu'!
ささいなことで
Pouting over
スネちゃうなんて初恋かしらって
small things, is this first love?
アキレスデール
Achilles' heel?
ウィンナーにははむかうつもり
I intend to resist the wiener!
アイビキしたら
If we have an 'aibiki' date,
ハラミて！ステーキ
look at the harami! It's steak-y!
オーイ！
Oh!
にくにくしい...
So meaty...
あなたは なぜか今日は ふしぎ顔
For some reason, you have a strange look on your face today.
きっと あれかしら
I wonder if it's that.
たんぱく質が足りないのね
You're lacking protein, aren't you?
ミートとユーとの ジョーシーなおにく
Juicy meat between Meat and You.
ユーとミートの げんきなえいえいよう！
Energetic nutrition between You and Meat!
ミートとユーとの ジョーシーなおにく
Juicy meat between Meat and You.
ユーとミートの ハッピーなおにく
Happy meat between You and Meat.
だいすき！
I love it!
国産のおにく 国産のおにく
Domestic meat, domestic meat.
にっくにく じゃぱねすく
Niku Niku Japonesque.
だいすきよー
I love you...
あなたとひとつになれるのならば
...if I can become one with you.
こんな幸せはないわー
...there is no greater happiness than this.
お味はいかが？
How does it taste?
黒毛和牛上塩タン焼 680円
Kuroge Wagyu Premium Salted Tongue Roast 680 Yen
ずーっと会いたくて待ってたの
I've been waiting to meet you all this time.
網の上に優しく寝かせて
Gently lay me down on the grill.
あなたにほてらされてあたしは色が変わるくらい
Heated by you until my color changes.
キラキラ光る粒の飾りで
Adorned with sparkling grains...
オシャレ
...so stylish.
だいすきよー
I love you...
もっともっと あたしを愛して
...love me more and more.
だいすきよー
I love you...
あなたとひとつになれるのならば
...if I can become one with you.
こんな幸せはないわ
There is no greater happiness than this.
お味はいかが？
How does it taste?
ということで、やってきました！白銀ノエル生誕祭2023！
And so, here we are! Shirogane Noel's Birthday Celebration 2023!
イエーイ！おめでとう！
Yay! Congratulations!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
はい、ということで、改めて司会を務めさせていただきます。鼻声の天音かなたです。イエーイ！
Yes, so once again, I'll be serving as your MC. I'm Amane Kanata, with a stuffy nose. Yay!
大丈夫？ / 鼻声ですが、大丈夫です
Are you okay? / She has a stuffy nose, but she's fine.
そして、本日の主役のー！
And today's guest of honor...!
わーい！どうも主役です、誕生日です！ホロライブ3期生の白銀ノエルです！イエーイ！
Yay! I'm the star, it's my birthday! I'm Shirogane Noel of Hololive's 3rd Generation! Yay!
イエーイ！おめでとう！
Yay! Congratulations!
そして、お馴染みの豪華ゲストの皆さんでございます。はい！
And here are our familiar and wonderful guests. Go ahead!
こんふぁーれ！豪華ゲストのひとり、ホロライブ3期生の不知火フレアです！イエーイ！
Kon-Flare! One of the special guests, Shiranui Flare from Hololive 3rd Gen! Yay!
自分で言っちゃったｗ
She said it herself lol.
こんぺこー！豪華ゲストのひとり、兎田ぺこらっぺこー！イエーイ！
Kon-Peko! One of the special guests, Usada Pekora-peko! Yay!
Ahoy! 同じく豪華ゲストのひとり、宝鐘マリンです。イエーイ！
Ahoy! Likewise, one of the special guests, Houshou Marine here. Yay!
今日は、団長が誕生日祝いに牛丼を振る舞ってくれるという話で皆さん呼ばれていたと思うんですけど...
Today, everyone was invited here on the premise that Danchou would be treating us to beef bowls to celebrate her birthday...
ま、なぜか、関係のない僕が司会を務めさせてもらっております。
But for some reason, I, who have nothing to do with it, am serving as the MC.
えー！だってやっぱり司会と言ったらかなたんっしょ！っていうね！
Ehh! But when it comes to MCing, it's gotta be Kanatan! Right?
あら、ありがとう！赤身コンビですからね！
Oh, thank you! We are the lean meat duo, after all!
ま、ちょっと今日は鼻声だけど…あと皆さん、ちょっと気づきませんか？なんか、クイズ番組っぽい…
Well, I have a stuffy nose today... but also, don't you all notice? It feels kind of like a quiz show...
確かに、何だ、不穏だなこれ。
True, what is this? This feels ominous.
牛丼食べるだけって感じじゃないよね。
It doesn't feel like we're just here to eat beef bowls.
いやでもこれ、あれですよ、牛丼を置く机ね、これ。
No, but look, this is just a table to put the beef bowl on.
ああ、食卓ねｗ
Ah, a dining table lol.
何が始まるんです？
What's about to start?
いやー、まあまあ、ちょっと皆さんとりあえず落ち着いてもらっていいっすか？
Whoa, whoa, could everyone just calm down for a second?
えーっと、今日はね、団長と一緒にね、誕生日だからわーって食べてもらう感じだったんですけども...
Um, today was supposed to be a thing where you all just eat excitedly with me since it's my birthday, but...
なんかちょっと準備が楽しすぎて…ということで団長、急遽…
Well, the preparations were just too much fun, so I...
究極牛丼を、あの、作る旅に出て、きた！
I've come back from a journey to make the ultimate beef bowl!
おー、いつの間に旅に。
Oh, when did you go on a journey?
究極牛丼？
Ultimate beef bowl?
何ですかそれは。
What's that?
出てきました。ということで。
I went. So...
何の説明もしてねえ！
You haven't explained anything!
説明しろよ。
Explain it!
ざっくりだな。ということで、まあ、ちょっと、ここらへんの雛壇とかは置いといて、とりあえずVTRどうぞ。
That's brief. Anyway, let's put aside the panel here for now, and please watch the VTR.
VTR？何？
VTR? What?
雑だなおい！
You're being so rough!
白銀ノエルにとって“牛丼”とは？
What is "Gyudon" to Shirogane Noel?
牛丼。
Gyudon.
それは団長にとっての...
It is a...
...完全食なんです。
...complete meal for the Danchou.
まあ、完全食の理由は...
Well, the reason it's a complete meal...
...みなさんお分かり...
...as you all know...
...めちゃめちゃ美味しいから。
...is because it's so incredibly delicious.
誕生日も来ますし...
My birthday is coming up...
...ずっと叶えたかった夢を、団長、叶えようと思うんです。
...and I, Danchou, want to make a dream I've had for a long time come true.
究極の牛丼を作るという夢。
The dream of making the ultimate beef bowl.
牛丼において大事なのは...
What's important...
...肉、玉ねぎ。
...in a beef bowl is the meat and the onions.
この２つの食材は特に重要っすよね。
These two ingredients are especially important, right?
行くしかない。やるしかない。
I have to go. I have to do it.
白銀ノエル、究極牛丼を作る旅に出やす！
Shirogane Noel is heading out on a journey to make the ultimate beef bowl!
行ってきやす！
Off I go!
牛丼大好き。牛丼が好きすぎる女騎士、白銀ノエル。
Loves beef bowls. The female knight who loves beef bowls too much, Shirogane Noel.
彼女が求めるのは、究極の牛丼。
What she seeks is the ultimate beef bowl.
長年の夢を叶えるべく、彼女が向かった先とは...
To fulfill her long-held dream, where she headed was...
ノエ旅 あびゃびゃ！ 全国おいしい発見！ ～高級食材で牛丼づくりに挑む～ ナレーション AZKi
Noe-tabi Abyabya! Nationwide Delicious Discovery! ~Taking on the challenge of making a beef bowl with high-end ingredients~ Narration: AZKi
みなさーん、こんまっする〜！
Hello everyone, Kon-muscle!
牛丼ハンター、白銀ノエルです。
Beef bowl hunter, Shirogane Noel.
やってきました、兵庫県神戸市内。
I've arrived in Kobe City, Hyogo Prefecture.
こちら、神戸大橋です。
This is the Kobe Ohashi bridge.
でけ〜！風つえ〜！
It's huge! The wind is strong!
団長のお目当てはここ神戸にあります。
Danchou's goal is here in Kobe.
神戸のお肉と言ったら？
Speaking of Kobe meat?
そう、神戸牛！
Yes, Kobe Beef!
まずは神戸牛をゲットしに行きます。
First, I'm going to go get some Kobe Beef.
うお〜！
Whoa!
1868年神戸港開港。日本でも急速に食肉文化が発展。
1868, Kobe Port opens. Meat-eating culture develops rapidly in Japan.
神戸牛やブランド牛は世界に名を轟かせてきました。
Kobe Beef and other brand-name beef have become world-famous.
しかし、そのブランド牛の始祖となる牛が、ここ兵庫から生まれていたことを。
However, [did you know] the ancestor of those brand cows was born here in Hyogo?
その牛の名は...
The name of that cow is...
但馬牛。
Tajima Beef.
但馬牛を求め、とある牧場へ向かった。
Seeking Tajima Beef, she headed to a certain ranch.
いや〜、ここが兵庫か。空が青い！
Man, so this is Hyogo. The sky is so blue!
山がデカい！
The mountains are huge!
すごい大自然を感じま...
I can feel the great nature...
ちょっと待ってください。
Wait a second.
今、地面が揺れた。
The ground just shook.
これは、600キロの波動がいくつも連なったもの。
This is the vibration of several 600kg beings linked together.
今、風の知らせで、牧草の香りがします。
Right now, on the wind, I smell the pasture.
牧草、そして600キロの波動。これはA5ランクの神戸牛が近くにいる。
The pasture, and the 600kg vibration. This means A5 rank Kobe beef is nearby.
つまり団長が探している但馬牛がいる。
In other words, the Tajima beef Danchou is looking for is here.
じゃあ、ちょっとここらへんを重点的に探索してみましょう。行ってきます！
Well then, let's explore this area thoroughly. Here I go!
お〜、何かここらへんにA5ランクの良い牛さんがいるような匂いがしますね。
Oh, I smell some good A5 rank cows around here.
すみませ〜ん、こんにちは。
Excuse me, hello.
こんにちは。
Hello.
もしかしてこの牛さんたちは全て...？
Are these cows all...?
ここにいるのは全部、メスの但馬牛になります。
The ones here are all female Tajima cows.
県外の牛と比べて、ちょっと小柄ではあるのですが、脂肪や赤身の質が良いという特徴があります。
Compared to cows from outside the prefecture, they're a bit small, but they feature high-quality fat and lean meat.
団長のことを見つめてます。
She's staring at Danchou.
もしかしたら団長の子とが好きかもしれないんで、ちょっと触れ合ってみたいと思います。
Maybe she likes Danchou, so I'd like to interact with her a bit.
今、団長の手をペロペロしてくれました！
She just licked Danchou's hand!
すごく、生暖かいです。
It's very... lukewarm.
これが美味しいタンになるんだね。ありがとね。
This is going to become delicious tongue, isn't it? Thank you.
A5ランクの神戸牛候補生ってことですよね？
So she's an A5 rank Kobe Beef candidate, right?
はい、厳しい審査を通過した但馬牛が神戸ビーフとなります。
Yes, Tajima beef that passes strict inspections becomes Kobe Beef.
実は、神戸牛という品種は存在しません。厳しい評価基準をクリアした特別な但馬牛が、神戸牛と名乗ることを許されているのです。
Actually, there's no such breed as "Kobe Beef." Only special Tajima beef that clears strict evaluation standards is allowed to be called Kobe Beef.
さらに、日本が誇るブランド和牛。そのルーツのほとんどが但馬牛であり...
Furthermore, Japan's pride brand wagyu. Most of their roots are Tajima beef...
全国黒毛和牛の99.9%が但馬牛の血を引いている。
And 99.9% of Japanese Black wagyu nationwide carry the blood of Tajima beef.
黒毛和牛の99.9%が但馬牛の血を引いている
99.9% of Japanese Black cattle carry Tajima cattle blood.
但馬牛という品種を生んだ田尻号
Tajiri-go, the bull that gave rise to the Tajima breed.
但馬牛の元牛となったのが、田尻号という牛なのですが...
The bull that became the sire of Tajima cattle was one named Tajiri-go...
それでは、この牛舎の前で、クエスチョンです！
Now then, in front of this cattle shed, here's a question!
Q. 田尻号は生涯で何頭の子孫を残した？
Q. How many offspring did Tajiri-go leave in his lifetime?
田尻号ですが、生涯で何頭の子孫を残したでしょうか？
Regarding Tajiri-go, how many offspring did he leave in his lifetime?
みんな、わかるかな～？
Does everyone know?
わかるかな～？
田尻号って単体だよね？一人で何匹産んだかって話だよね？
Tajiri-go is a single individual, right? So it's about how many he sired by himself?
そうです。あびゃ！
That's right. Abya!
この問題含めて、これから計3問ほどクイズが出ます、皆さん。
Including this problem, there will be a total of about three quiz questions from now on, everyone.
1問正解できたら1ptゲットで、
If you get one correct, you get 1 point, and...
合計5ptゲットできたら牛丼を食べる権利が与えられますが...
if you get a total of 5 points, you'll be given the right to eat a beef bowl...
え、なんかおかしくね？
Wait, isn't that a bit weird?
分かりましたか？やはり突っ込まれるんじゃない？
Did you notice? I thought someone would point it out.
賢い皆さんはすぐに分かる。クイズの数と合計ptが合っていませんよね。
You clever people noticed right away. The number of quizzes and the total points don't match, do they?
安心してください。皆さんにはあらかじめ2体の団員さんが与えられております！
Rest assured. You have all been given two 'Members' in advance!
え、どういうこと？あ！団員さん出てきた！ニョキニョキじゃん！
Wait, what do you mean? Oh! The members appeared! They popped up!
ということでね、この団員さんでございますが、
So, regarding these members...
クイズの回答に自信がありましたら、
if you are confident in your quiz answer...
団員さんをマックス2体までBET、賭けることができます！
you can BET or wager up to two of them!
そして賭けて正解した場合、1体につき2倍のポイントがゲットできます！
And if you wager and get it right, you'll get double the points for each!
団員さんは使い回しでまたBET出来る訳ではないので、使い所は要検討。
You can't reuse the members to bet again, so consider carefully when to use them.
ここが絶対に当てるっていう時に、ぜひね使ってみてください。
When you're absolutely sure you'll get it right, please do give it a try.
不正解の場合は、BETした団員さんの数だけ没収となります！
In case of an incorrect answer, as many members as you bet will be confiscated!
いなくなりますから、そこから。消えます。
They'll be gone from there. They'll disappear.
一旦団員さんはしまっちゃおうね。バイバイ。
Let's put the members away for now. Bye-bye.
ということで、それでは。団員さんをBETしたいという方は、
And so, then. Those who want to bet members...
回答後にBETするか否かを教えてください。
please let me know whether you'll bet or not after answering.
5ptゲットを目指して皆さん頑張りましょう！
Let's all do our best aiming for 5 points!
おー！頑張るぞ！イエーイ！牛丼のため！
Oh! Let's do it! Yay! For the sake of beef bowls!
ま、ちなみに司会の僕はクイズしなくても食べられますよね？牛丼。
Well, by the way, as the host, I can eat beef bowls even without doing the quiz, right?
いやそれは勿論ですよ。あびゃ！よかった！
No, of course you can. Abya! Glad to hear it!
え、ずるくね？やったーじゃねえよ！
Wait, isn't that unfair? Don't 'yay' me!
え？知ってる？お前聞いてるんだろ答え！なんで参加してんだよ！
Huh? You know? You've heard the answer, haven't you! Why are you participating then!
だって... こっちのほうが楽しそうだって思ったんだもん！
But... I thought this side looked more fun!
答えさせるや！
Let me answer!
全問正解は当たり前だよね、団長はね、そうなると。
Getting every question right is a given for the Captain, then.
も、もちろん。まあでも5点目指し...
O-Of course. Well, but aiming for 5 points...
ルール説明もできましたので、早速、回答記入タイムに入ります。どうぞ！
Now that the rules have been explained, we'll head straight into the answer entry time. Go!
子孫、子孫。田尻号は13年間で何頭子孫を残した？
Offspring, offspring. How many offspring did Tajiri-go leave in 13 years?
13年だよ！13年！長いです。
It's 13 years! 13 years! That's a long time.
ちなみに田尻号はですね、オスの牛さん、雄牛でございますから...
By the way, Tajiri-go is a male cow, a bull...
はいはいはい、仕込むってことね。種をね。
Right, right, right, so he 'seeds' them. The seeds.
和牛の偉大なる父と呼ばれている。
He is called the great father of Wagyu.
13年の間で何頭の子孫を残したか、ということでございますから。
So it's about how many offspring he left in those 13 years.
いや～たくさんいてほしいな～。たくさんいてほしい...
Man, I hope there are many of them. I want there to be many...
どういう感想ぺこよ... バキバキ。
What kind of feedback is that, peko... Baki baki.
皆さん、記入はどうですか？できましたか？
Everyone, how is the writing going? Are you done?
はい。できました！お願いします！
Yes. Done! Please go ahead!
はい、それでは皆さん記入できたようなので。
Alright, it seems everyone's finished writing.
じゃあ、まず団長以外の3人の回答を。
Then, first the answers of the three besides the Captain.
一斉に表示していきましょう。どうぞ！
Let's display them all at once. Go!
これぐらいかな。無限！
About this much. Infinity!
何？無限？バカじゃないの！何でだよ！
What? Infinity? Are you stupid! Why!
数えられねえんだよ、基本的に！
You basically can't count them!
13年間でもう終わってんの！一匹一匹数えてられませんよ！
After 13 years, it's already over! You can't count them one by one!
え、確かに。血が入っていれば何でもいいよ！
Wait, true. If they have the blood, anything goes!
数えられるわけねーじゃん！
There's no way you can count them!
どこで産んでるかなんて分かんないところだってあるかもしれないんだから！
Because there might be places where they're born and we don't even know!
そうだよ！おバカ！数字書いてんじゃねえよ！
That's right! Stupid! Stop writing numbers!
ではフレアさんの回答からちょっと見ていきましょう。120ということで。
Then, let's take a look at Flare-san's answer. It's 120.
希望的観測を込めたんだけど、少なかったかもしれない。120くらいかなと。
I put some wishful thinking into it, but it might be too low. Maybe about 120.
自信ありますか？全然ないです。
Are you confident? Not at all.
基準がどれぐらいなんだろうっていうのが分からないけど...
I don't know what the baseline would be...
じゃあこれは団員さんBETはしま...？せんっ！
So, will you bet any members...? I won't!
せんか。なるほど。それじゃあ次は無限大のぺこら先輩。
You won't. I see. Then next, infinity for Pekora-senpai.
だってお牛さんでいちいちそんな誰と誰が... みたいな...
Because they're cows, and one by one, who with whom... like...
照れてんじゃねーよ！
Don't act all shy!
田尻号さんでしたっけ？
Was it Tajirigo-san?
はい。もういくつもの雌牛とさ、いろいろとさ、やってるかもしれないけど…
Yes. He might have been active with many cows and such, but...
そうですよ。数えられるわけなくね？普通に。
That's right. There's no way you can count them, right? Normally.
ちゅうことは無限しかないの！誰も数えられないからじゃあ無限にしましょうか。
That means it can only be infinity! Since no one can count them, let's go with infinity.
お前団員賭けろもうそれ。
You should bet your "Danyin" on that.
行くしかねぇよ。／団員賭けよう。／賭けようぜぺこら。／します？
There's no other way. / Let's bet the "Danyin". / Let's bet, Pekora. / Will you do it?
わかったよ…団員…
Alright... "Danyin"...
MAX2行く！
Going with the maximum of 2!
行くしかねぇよ！／すごーい！／マジですげー！
You have to go for it! / Amazing! / That's really amazing!
こいつら賭けて。え、×2なんだよね？正解したら。
I'm betting these guys. It'll be doubled, right? If I get it right.
そうですよ。
That's right.
行け無限！じゃあ行きましょうか。
Go infinity! Well then, shall we proceed?
それではあとはマリンですね。マリンの回答は？
Now, only Marine is left. What is Marine's answer?
マリンの回答これね、ちょっとパッと見380頭に見えるんですけど、よくよく見ると無限なんですね。
This is Marine's answer. It might look like 380 at a glance, but if you look closely, it's infinity.
なんで380の80にしたぺこの？
Why did you turn the 8 of 380 into an 80, Peko?
え、これは…13…ちょっと待って。ちょっと待って。
Uh, this is... 13... wait a minute. Wait a minute.
そんなこといちいち聞くんじゃないでしょう？
You shouldn't ask that every single time, right?
お前もBETするんだよな！ぺこらにも懸けた。BETするよな？380頭でBETするよな！？
You're going to bet too, aren't you! You challenged Pekora. You'll bet, right? Bet with 380, right!?
まぁ一旦いいか、一旦。
No, well, for now it's fine, for now.
ふざけるなよ！一旦いいかって。BETはしないということで。
Don't mess with me! What do you mean "for now it's fine"? So you're not betting.
最初の問題でいきなりBETする奴ってバカですよね。
Anyone who bets right on the first question is an idiot, right?
お前吹っ掛けてきただろう！ふざけるな！2体使ってでもMAXなんだよこいつら！
You were the one who suggested it! Don't mess with me! I'm using two of them, and it's their max!
でも自信あるんでしょ？
But you're confident, right?
まぁ自信あるわ。
Well, I am.
じゃあまぁ皆さん最後に団長の答えを見ていきましょう。／こちら！
Well then, everyone, let's see the Captain's answer last. / This one!
牛丼だ！「おにくおいしい」頭です。
It's a beef bowl! It's "Meat is delicious" heads.
まぁまぁまぁまぁ、いいですね。熱量が。
Well, well, well, it's fine. The passion...
これに関しては団長答え知らない…
Regarding this, the Captain doesn't know the answer...
ええ？聞いてないの？そういうパターンもあるんだ。
Eh? You haven't heard? There are patterns like that too.
ちなみにんなんですけど団長、BETはしますか？
By the way, Captain, will you bet?
でも団員さんの顔見たい！見たいからちょっと…
But I want to see the "Danyin's" face! I want to see it, so...
はい、1匹ちょっと見たいな。1匹BETさせてもらうね。
Yes, I want to see one. I'll let one of them bet.
オーケイでございますよ。さよなら団員さん。
Understood. Goodbye, "Danyin"-san.
さぁそれでは皆さん、正解した方はいらっしゃるんでしょうか。
Now then, everyone, is there anyone who got it right?
それでは正解を発表します。こちらです！
Now, I will announce the answer. It's this!
13年間でなんと、約1500頭！
In 13 years, amazingly, approximately 1500 heads!
すごい！もっといたんだけど！
Amazing! I thought there were more!
田尻号が自然交配でなんと1500頭ほど子孫を残してくれたというね。
Tajirigo left behind about 1500 offspring through natural mating.
約1500だよ？無限と同じじゃないですか！
It's approx 1500, right? Isn't it the same as infinity!?
司会者権限でどうぺこですかこれは？
As the MC, what's the verdict on this, Peko?
残念ながらでございます。
Unfortunately, you're wrong.
思考放棄、思考放棄～
Thought abandonment, thought abandonment~
全員不正解、0ptです！
Everyone is wrong, 0 points!
没収しないで！
Don't confiscate them!
ぺこら選手、そしてノエル団長の団員さんは没収！
Pekora and Noel's "Danyin" are confiscated!
バイバイ～／さようなら。
Bye bye~ / Goodbye.
まだまだ挽回のチャンス皆さんありますから。頑張っていきましょう。
There are still chances to make a comeback. Let's keep working hard.
それではVTRの続きどうぞ！
Well then, please continue with the VTR!
牛丼ハンターノエルは、但馬牛の肉質をその目で見極めるため…
Beef bowl hunter Noel, in order to judge the quality of Tajima beef with her own eyes...
肉処 たつきさんへと向かいました。
...headed to Nikudokoro Tatsuki.
今から枝肉を食肉にする作業をご覧いただければと思います。
I would like you to see the process of turning raw meat into table meat.
ぜひ見たいです。よろしくお願いします。
I'd definitely love to see it. Thank you.
おぉ～すごい！
Ooh~ Amazing!
分厚いお肉がどんどん切られてます。
The thick meat is being sliced more and more.
脂身を削いで、どんどんどんどん滑らかになってる。
Shaving off the fat, it's becoming smoother and smoother.
これがプロの手さばき。
This is professional handiwork.
断面図！すごいサシ！
Cross-section! Amazing marbling!
但馬牛が絶賛される理由のひとつ…
One of the reasons Tajima beef is so highly acclaimed...
…に、このサシの良さがあります。
...this is the beauty of the marbling.
しなやかで締まりの良い筋肉が
Pliable, firm muscles...
良質な脂肪を内面に留まらせて生まれるこの美しいサシが生まれるのです。
...retain high-quality fat within, creating this beautiful marbling.
牛丼ハンター白銀ノエル、あとは部位を決めるのみ。
Gyudon Hunter Shirogane Noel, now all that's left is to decide on the cut.
究極の牛丼に合う部位はどこか、その味を確かめるため…
To find the cut that best suits the ultimate gyudon and confirm its taste...
精肉店からすぐの場所にある、川岸牧場グループ店舗、肉料理 樹にお邪魔しました。
...we visited Niku Ryori Tatsuki, a Kawagishi Farm group store located right near the butcher shop.
早速なんですけど、どの部位がいいか迷ってて…
Right off the bat, I'm undecided on which cut would be best...
オススメとか教えていただければなと思っております。
...so I was hoping you could give me some recommendations.
一応本日、あの、3種類ご用意させてもらいました。
Well, today I've prepared three types for you.
用意してもらった部位はこちらの3種。
These are the three cuts prepared.
この中に牛丼ハンターノエルが納得する部位はあるのでしょうか。
Will Gyudon Hunter Noel find one she's satisfied with among them?
まずはサーロインからいただいていきます。
First, let's try the sirloin.
うわー！いい匂いがもうすでに漂ってきてるんですけど。
Wow! A great aroma is already wafting over.
背中中央部のお肉で脂乗りがよく、きめ細かくやわらかい食感の部位です。
This is the meat from the center of the back; it's well-marbled, fine-textured, and soft.
これってどれぐらい焼けばいいんですか？
How much should I grill this?
片面をしっかり焼いていただいて、焦げ目がしっかり付くので…
Grill one side thoroughly until it's well-browned...
そのタイミングで裏返しもらえたらなと。
...and at that point, please flip it over.
おおー、すげぇ。
Ooh, amazing.
じゃ、いただきます。
Well then, let's eat.
美味しい！柔らかくて甘い。
Delicious! It's tender and sweet.
続いては、あの、芯ロースを焼いていただければ。
Next, if you could grill the shin-roast.
肩の芯の部分を抜き取ったお肉で、適度な脂があり、柔らかいながらも噛み応えのある食感の部位です。
This meat is taken from the core of the shoulder; it has moderate fat and a texture that is soft yet chewy.
ほどよく噛み応えもあり、でも柔らかく、すごく美味しいです。
It has a nice chew but is also soft; it's very delicious.
結構牛丼って赤身肉が多いんで、いいかもしれないですね。
Gyudon usually has a lot of lean meat, so this might be a good choice.
次は赤身の部位で、特選のクリを。
Next is a lean cut, the specially selected 'kuri'.
団長クリって聞いたことないんですけど、どういった部位になるんですかね？
I've never heard of 'kuri' before; what kind of cut is it?
クリは、肩から前脚上部にかけての部位に。味わい深いすごい歯応えのある部位になります。
'Kuri' is the cut from the shoulder to the upper foreleg. It's a very flavorful cut with a firm bite.
いただきます。
Let's eat.
美味しいです。
It's delicious.
先程と違う匂いを感じますよ。但馬牛の香りはすごく、あの、やっぱり鼻に残るというか。
I notice a different aroma than before. The scent of Tajima beef really lingers in the nose.
やっぱり牛丼って言ったら、こういう赤身肉が今イメージに浮かんでるんですけど…
When it comes to gyudon, I'm picturing this kind of lean meat now, but...
いや、美味しいんで。いや、悩むな。
Gosh, it's so good. Man, I'm torn.
これはもうここまで来たら、いろんなお肉を食べないと結論がつかないかなって思うんで…
At this point, I don't think I can reach a conclusion without trying various meats...
まず牛丼を見立てて米と、あとはねぎ塩タンと…
First, imagining the gyudon with rice, and then the negi-shio tongue...
サーロインのユッケがあるって聞いたんですけど。
I heard you have sirloin yukke (steak tartare).
あります。
We do.
一旦それで考えるとかでもいいですかね？
Would it be okay if I based my decision on that for a bit?
お言葉に甘えて色々選ばせていただきます。
I'll take you up on that and choose a few things.
別に団長が食べたいわけではないので… いただきます。
It's not that I just want to eat them... Let's eat.
果たして究極の牛丼に、サーロインのユッケは関係あるのか。お味のほどは。
Will the sirloin yukke play a role in the ultimate gyudon? How does it taste?
贅沢にいっぱい黄身をつけて、こちらいただきたいと思います。
I'll dip it generously in the egg yolk and try it.
今まで食べたユッケ系で一番美味しいです。
It's the best yukke-style dish I've ever had.
団長最近ちょっと鉄の胃袋大魔神と言いつつも、脂にちょっと負け気味なんですけど…
Lately, despite calling myself the Iron Stomach Demon God, I've been feeling a bit overwhelmed by fat...
このユッケだったら脂っこさも感じず、スルッと食べられて。
...but with this yukke, I don't feel the greasiness; it goes down smoothly.
これを牛丼にしたら面白そうですよね。
It sounds like it would be interesting to turn this into gyudon.
試食を終え、牛丼ハンターノエルが選ぶ、究極の牛丼とは。
After the tasting, what is the ultimate gyudon that Gyudon Hunter Noel chooses?
どれも美味しくてめちゃめちゃ悩むんですけど、最後に食べたサーロインのユッケがどうしても忘れられないのと…
Everything was so delicious I'm really torn, but I just can't forget that sirloin yukke I ate last...
クリが聞いたこともないし、あとほどよく赤身で…
...and 'kuri' is something I've never heard of, plus it's a nice lean cut...
この2つを組み合わせて究極牛丼を作ろうかなと思うんですけど、どうですかね？
So I'm thinking of combining these two to make the ultimate gyudon. What do you think?
すごく良いと思います。
I think it's a great idea.
じゃあこの2つの部位を究極牛丼に使いたいので、何卒いただくことはできませんでしょうか。
Then, since I want to use these two cuts for my ultimate gyudon, could I please have them?
オッケーです！大丈夫です！
Okay! No problem!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ということで、一番の目当てだった神戸牛をゲットしました！
And so, I've secured the Kobe beef, which was my main goal!
続いて牛丼ハンターノエルが向かった先は？ たまねぎ、たまねぎ…
Next, where did Gyudon Hunter Noel head? Onions, onions...
ということで、淡路島に来ております。
And so, I've come to Awaji Island.
淡路といえばたまねぎ！
Awaji means onions!
団長、牛丼は甘めでシャキシャキのたまねぎが好き。
I like my gyudon to be a bit sweet with crunchy onions.
ここで最高のたまねぎ見つけるぞい！
I'm going to find the best onions here!
牛丼に欠かせない食材、たまねぎ。
Onions, an indispensable ingredient for gyudon.
究極のたまねぎを求めて訪れたのは、株式会社善太さんのフルーツたまねぎ農園。
Seeking the ultimate onion, we visited Zenta Co., Ltd.'s Fruit Onion Farm.
あそこに人がいますね。
There's someone over there.
おーい！作業中に申し訳ないですけどお話聞いてもいいですか？
Hey! Sorry to interrupt your work,
but may I talk to you for a moment?
はーい、行きまーす。
Yes! I'm coming.
すいません、お仕事中に。
Sorry to bother you while you're working.
いえいえ、大丈夫ですよ。
No, no, it's fine.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ちなみに先ほど何をされていたんですか？
By the way, what were you doing just now?
今は玉ねぎを植え付けしておりました。
I was planting onions just now.
ここらへんは全部玉ねぎ畑ってことで？
So this whole area is an onion field?
団長が探してたやつです！ありがとうございます！
This is what I was looking for! Thank you!
今お手元に持たれているのは？
What are you holding in your hand?
うちで獲れたフルーツ玉ねぎです。
It's a 'Fruit Onion' grown here.
フルーツ玉ねぎ！？めちゃめちゃ甘いっちゅうこと？
Fruit Onion!? Does that mean it's incredibly sweet?
フルーツぐらい甘い玉ねぎです。
It's an onion as sweet as fruit.
レンジでチンした柔らかくした玉ねぎがあるんで...
I have some onions softened in the microwave...
よかったらそれを試食してもらって。
...so if you'd like, please try some.
ありがとうございます。いただきます。
Thank you. I'll have some.
ん〜！甘い！こりゃ美味い！
Mmm! Sweet! This is delicious!
フルーツ玉ねぎ 最高糖度11度で甘さは梨やみかんと同程度
Fruit Onion: Max sugar content 11%, sweetness comparable to pears and oranges.
玉ねぎ畑の前からクエスチョンです！
A question from in front of the onion field!
Q. 淡路フルーツ玉ねぎがめちゃくちゃ甘い理由は？
Q. Why are Awaji Fruit Onions so incredibly sweet?
ヒントはこの絶景！
The hint is this superb view!
この絶景
This superb view
はい！ということで回答記入タイムでございます！
Alright! It's time to write down your answers!
難しい〜、景色関係あるの？
It's hard. Does the view have anything to do with it?
景色っていうとね…やっぱり何だろうな。
When you say view... I wonder what it is.
育つのに何が必要かなってことだよね。
It's about what's needed for growth, right?
何か違うところあるよね、普通の畑と。
There's something different about it
compared to normal fields.
分かった！分かった！ノエル先輩！
I got it! I got it! Noel-senpai!
マリンのあの大富豪のやつ全部ぺこらに寄越して！
Give all of Marin's 'Millionaire' points to Pekora!
何でよ！
Why?!
あれじゃない？
Isn't it that?
待って、マリンもひらめいたわ。
Wait, Marin's got an idea too.
お前の浮かれっぷりを見てひらめきました。
I got it by looking at how excited you are.
甘い理由か〜…
The reason for its sweetness, huh...
どうでしょうか？
How about it?
これ自信あるわ！さっきのに賭ければよかった！
I'm confident! I should've bet on this instead!
なぞにウキウキだったじゃん。
You were mysteriously excited.
はー、これだわ絶対。他と違うぺこだもん。
Hah, this is definitely it.
It feels different from the others, Peko.
あそこに映ってるからね。あれはヒントでした。
It's all reflected over there. That was the hint.
あーじゃあこれだ！じゃあこれだ！
Ah, then it's this! Then it's this!
漢字簡単だけどぺこら馬鹿だから書けない？
The Kanji is easy but since Pekora is an idiot,
she can't write it?
はー？あー今それで悩んでた。
Huh? Ah, that's what I was just worrying about.
ノエルはこれ答え知ってんの？
Noel, do you know the answer to this?
うん！知ってる〜！
Yep! I know it!
忘れてたからぺこちゃんの今の...
I'd forgotten it, but Pekora saying...
「映像に映ってる」っていうので思い出した。
...'it's in the footage' reminded me.
自分で出したヒントじゃないですか！
It was the hint you gave yourself!
確かに、自分で言ったのに。
True, even though I said it myself.
さあマリンはどうですか？
Now, Marin, how about you?
いやもう、これで…オッケー！いきますよ！
Well, with this... OK! Here I go!
それでは回答が出揃いましたので。
Alright, now that all the answers are in...
団長以外の3人の回答を表示しましょう！
Let's display the answers from the other three!
フレア：気温の変化 / ぺこら：潮風 / マリン：絶景の海水(上質)を吸っている
Flare: Temp change / Pekora: Sea breeze / Marin: Absorbing superb seawater
待って、なんて書いてあんのそれ？潮風？風？
Wait, what's written there? Sea breeze? Breeze?
スイカとかに塩かけたら甘くなるだろ！
If you put salt on watermelon, it gets sweeter!
潮風にドンドンドンって当たった玉ねぎが甘くなる！
Onions hit by the sea breeze grow sweet!
玉ねぎって根菜だから下で育ってんじゃないの？
Onions are root vegetables,
so aren't they growing underground?
上にこうやってなってたっけ？下じゃない？
Were they sticking out like that?
Isn't it underground?
ぺこら、潮風当たる？ねえ。
Pekora, does the sea breeze reach them? Hey.
潮風が吸い込んだ土で育つねん！お前は！
They grow in soil that's absorbed the sea breeze! You dummy!
上とか風じゃなくて潮風です。海見えたもん。
It's the sea breeze, not just wind. I saw the ocean.
マリンもですね、「絶景の海水(上質)を吸っている」。
Marin also has 'Absorbing superb seawater (high quality)'.
土が海のこの良い水を吸って育っていると。
The soil absorbs this good water from the sea and they grow.
海水で育ってたら玉ねぎ死んじゃうんじゃないの？
If they grew with seawater,
wouldn't the onions die?
それではマリン、どうですか？
Now, Marin, how about you?
ま、賭けるほどのことでもないよね。
Well, it's not something worth betting on, is it?
弱気！弱気だぞ！お前次で！次にかける？
Cowardly! You're being a coward!
You'll bet on the next one?
ではフレア先輩はどうでしょう？
Then, how about Flare-senpai?
全然関係ない気がしてきた〜。
I'm starting to feel like it's completely irrelevant.
「気温の変化」。景色関係ないじゃん。
'Temperature change'. The view has nothing to do with it.
お待ちかねの団長、ノエルの回答を決めちゃうぞー！
Let's decide on the answer from
the Knight-commander Noel!
決めちゃうぞー！ということで見ていきましょう！
Let's decide it! And with that, let's take a look!
三宅さんの笑顔♡
Miyake-san's smile ♡
三宅さんの笑顔♥ ノエル
Miyake-san's smile ♥ Noel
煽ってるよなー。ねー。
She's totally mocking him. Right?
でも、聞いてほしい。めっちゃ笑顔で！
But, please listen. He had a huge smile!
あっ、めっちゃ笑顔で！なんか、やっぱさ、あの関西だからゴテェゴテェの関西弁で...
Ah, with a huge smile! And since it's Kansai, he had a thick Kansai accent...
ノリのいい人で。いやぁ～これだったら甘くなるわ！って。
A person with such good vibes. I thought, "Man, with this, it's bound to be sweet!"
なるほどね。やっぱり、ちょっと声をかけると甘くなると。
I see. So, speaking to them makes them sweeter.
あ、そうそう。よくね植物とかね。綺麗、綺麗って言うとパァーッてなるから。だから甘い。
Oh, right. Like plants. If you say "beautiful, beautiful", they bloom. So that's why they're sweet.
待ったよ。マリンも最初に考えたのは、この景色を玉ねぎが見て育ってるって思ったの。
Wait. What I thought at first was that the onions were watching this scenery as they grew.
でも、よく考えたら根菜だから土の中か！って思って。
But then I thought, they're root vegetables so they're underground!
でも、こいつは、こいつは潮風受けてるって言ってきた。
But then this person said "they're receiving the sea breeze."
いやぁ、さぁどっちなんだろうな。
Well, I wonder which one it is.
どうですか？じゃ、団長これ自信のほうは...
How about it? So, Danchou, regarding your confidence...
あ、あるんですけど、まぁ今じゃない。
Ah, I have some, but well, not right now.
今、大印使うところではない。
Now is not the place to use my trump card.
そうですね。なるほど、わかりました。それでは、この中に正解者はいるのでしょうか？正解発表していきましょう！こちら！
True. I see, understood. Well then, is there a correct answer among these? Let's announce the correct answer! Here it is!
答え：ミネラルが土壌に含有されているため
Answer: Because minerals are contained in the soil
さあ、こちら！ミネラルが土壌に含有されているためでございます！
Well, here it is! Because minerals are contained in the soil!
潮風やん、これ。
That's the sea breeze.
はい。そういうわけでございました。ということで、これは土壌にミネラルが含まれているからということになります。
Yes. That's how it was. So, it's because the soil contains minerals.
淡路島の土壌にはですね、潮風などによって海のミネラルが染み込んでいるんです。
In the soil of Awaji Island, sea minerals have soaked in due to the sea breeze and other factors.
潮風
Sea breeze
などによって海のミネラルが
due to such factors, sea minerals
しみ込んでいるんです
have soaked in
なので、ミネラルが豊富な土壌は水はけがよく、余分な水分が玉ねぎに吸収されず甘くなるということで...
Therefore, soil rich in minerals has good drainage, and excess water isn't absorbed by the onions, making them sweet...
ミネラルが豊富な土壌は水はけがよく
Soil rich in minerals has good drainage,
余分な水分が玉ねぎに吸収されず
excess water isn't absorbed by the onions
甘くなるということで…
making them sweet...
ぺこら先輩、文句なしの大正解です！
Pekora-senpai, you're perfectly correct!
玉ねぎが風を浴びてるって言ってたじゃん！あのミネラルがね！
I said the onions were catching the breeze! Those minerals, you know!
まぁ、ちょっと省略してるということだからね！
Well, it means I just simplified it a bit!
いや、惜しいな～！マリンのもちょっと惜しかったけど、話を聞くと海水で育ったみたいな感じの全然違ったこと言ってたので、今回は残念ながら...
Ah, so close! Marine's was also a bit close, but hearing the explanation, you said something completely different like growing in seawater, so unfortunately this time...
総合的に私のほうが正解ってことで...
So overall, mine was the correct one...
何言ってんの！全然違うて！関係ないよ、お前は。
What are you saying! You're completely wrong! You're not related at all.
ということで、正解したぺこら先輩がプラス1ポイントとなりまして、計1ポイント。あとの3人、団長も含めて3人は残念ながら、まだ0ポイント。
So, Pekora-senpai who got it right gets plus 1 point, total 1 point. The other three, including Danchou, are unfortunately still at 0 points.
ま、ここから挽回していきますから。こちらには大印さんがいますからね。
Well, I'll make a comeback from here. I have my trump card over here.
待って、でも次正解しても4ポイントじゃね？あれ？ちょっと結構厳しいか？
Wait, but even if you get the next one right, it's 4 points, isn't it? Oh? Is it actually pretty tough?
足りないよ！
Not enough!
なんか、ちょっと牛丼食べられるか怪しくなってきましたね。
It's starting to look a bit suspicious whether you can eat the beef bowl.
まぁまぁ、でも諦めちゃダメですからね。まだ色んな可能性がございますから。大丈夫でございます。
Well, but you must not give up. There are still many possibilities. It'll be fine.
それでは、VTRの続き、どうぞ！
Well then, please continue with the VTR!
美味しかったです。ありがとうございます。
It was delicious. Thank you.
今ちょっと植え付けの途中で、玉ねぎの実物がちょっとないので、ちょっと倉庫のほうに保管してるやつを、よかったら。
Since we're in the middle of planting, we don't have any actual onions here, but if you'd like, we have some stored in the warehouse.
行きたいです！あの、大量にあるんですよね！？行きます！
I want to go! You have a lot, right!? Let's go!
本社倉庫を特別に見学
Special tour of the main warehouse
農園から30分ほど離れた本社にある倉庫内を、特別に見せていただくことに。
We were specially shown the inside of the warehouse at the main office, about 30 minutes away from the farm.
こちらが倉庫ですか？
Is this the warehouse?
そうですね。はい。この中に玉ねぎがいっぱい入ってます。
Yes. Inside here, there are many onions.
ここですか？なるほど。
Here? I see.
はい。じゃ、一度開けてみましょうか。
Yes. Well, let's open it once.
そうやって。おー！えー！これ全部玉ねぎですか？
Like that. Oh! Wow! Are all of these onions?
あ、すご。なんか冷気が。あと、なんかすごい寒いんですけど、これって何度とかなんですか？
Ah, amazing. There's a cold air. And it's really cold, what's the temperature?
今で2度くらい。1度、2度くらいです。
It's about 2 degrees now. About 1 or 2 degrees.
この2度で保管してるのは、何が理由があるんですか？
What's the reason for keeping it at 2 degrees?
玉ねぎの芽が出ないように、収穫した時の状態を保つためです。
To prevent the onions from sprouting, to maintain their state at harvest.
団長、先ほど食べさせていただいて、思い描いている牛丼にすごくイメージが合うなと思ったんですけど、どうですか？特徴とかも合いそうですか？
Danchou, having eaten it earlier, I thought the image fits the beef bowl I have in mind perfectly, but what do you think? Do the characteristics seem to match?
肉厚でジューシーで、非常に甘くて柔らかいので、合うと思います！
They are thick, juicy, very sweet and soft, so I think they'll fit!
太鼓判を押してもらって、なんかさらにちょっと牛丼のイメージが湧きました。
Getting your seal of approval has given me an even clearer image of the beef bowl.
ありがとうございます！善太さんの淡路フルーツ玉ねぎを、ぜひ究極の牛丼に使わせてください！
Thank you! Please let me use Zenta-san's Awaji Fruit Onions for the ultimate beef bowl!
究極牛丼 玉ねぎゲット！
Ultimate Beef Bowl Onions Get!
究極牛丼、玉ねぎゲット！やったー！
Ultimate beef bowl, onions get! Yay!
はい！ということでですね、ロケの様子のVTR見ていただきましたが、皆さんいかがでしたでしょうか？
Yes! So, we've seen the VTR of the location shoot, how was it everyone?
ステーキの部位も、この玉ねぎも初めてのフルーツ玉ねぎ。全部食べたことない！経験しないとこれは。
That cut of steak, and this onion too, it's my first time for fruit onions. I haven't eaten any of them! I have to experience this.
やっぱりみんな食べたいよね。
Everyone wants to eat it, after all.
食べたいということで...なんと後半はですね、まぁその集めた食材たちを使って、究極の牛丼を調理していく...
Since everyone wants to eat... in the second half, well, using those gathered ingredients, we will cook the ultimate beef bowl...
究極の牛丼を調理していく
I'm going to cook the ultimate beef bowl...
という様子を見てもらおうと思っているんですが...
...is what I was planning to show you, but...
が？
But?
ま、その前に、ライブパートでーす！
Well, before that, it's time for the live performance!
急に？
Suddenly?
ライブパート？
Live part?
ほめのび
Homenobi
練習中 シレっとこっそり準備進行
Practicing, quietly and secretly making progress
心象 緊張で焦る
Inner state: flustered with tension
言わんけど ツヨツヨありでしょ
I don't say it, but I'm strong, right?
元気配るから待っちょって
Wait for me, I'll be sharing some energy
そうやって成長する子です
That's how I grow
いいかな
Is it okay?
ゆるポでOK？
Is 'Yuru-po' okay?
テンパっちゃってOK
It's okay to panic
始めちゃお
Let's get started
ほめてほしいな ほめてほしいな
I want to be praised, I want to be praised
ほめてくれたら二倍増しで頑張る
If you praise me, I'll work twice as hard
見ててほしいな
I want you to watch me
ほめちぎられて伸びるタイプです
I'm the type that thrives on praise
ours
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ
It's not goodbye for today just yet
手をとってくれたのなら
If you would only take my hand
秘密を眠りにつくような夜に君を連れていくよ
In a night where secrets go to sleep, I'll take you with me
それはたとえ 遠く離れていたって
Even if we were to be far apart
手を繋いでいられるような奇跡のような
Like a miracle that allows us to stay hand-in-hand
話をしよう お窓は開けといて
Let's talk, keep the window open
今日までを思い出して
Recalling everything up until today
一つ一つ並べたら
Lining them up one by one
明日の雨が気になりだして
I start to worry about tomorrow's rain
どうも眠れないみたいだ
And I can't seem to sleep
変わりたくないことや
Things I don't want to change
変わらなきゃいけないことも
And things that must change
少し忘れたまま
Forgetting them a little
窓の外眺めていたんだ
I was gazing out the window
雨が降り出す その前に
Before the rain starts falling
君のところまで行けるような気がして
I feel like I can make it to where you are
目を閉じて そしてこのまま遠くへと行こう
Close your eyes, and let's go far away like this
手をとってくれるかな
Will you take my hand?
秘密を眠りにつくような夜を君と泳いでいくよ
In a night where secrets go to sleep, I'll swim through it with you
街の灯りが消えるたびに笑って
Laughing every time the city lights go out
路地裏で抱き合う
Embracing in the back alleys
バカみたいな話をしよう
Let's talk about silly things
窓は開けといて
Keep the window open
聞こえる？
Can you hear it?
聞こえる
I can hear it
ラブミーアンダー
Love Me Under
位置について よーいドンで 周回遅れで
On your mark, get set, go, a lap behind
明日は二周遅れ？
Tomorrow, two laps behind?
あのね 理由もなく夜明けになる日は
You know, on days when dawn comes for no reason
心が疲れてる証拠
It's proof that the heart is tired
でもね 笑う門には福も見に来てかもって
But they say fortune comes to those who laugh
Oh Baby What a Beautiful Day
うろ覚えの歌詞も
Vague lyrics I half-remember,
曖昧なメロディも
and ambiguous melodies too,
君と歌えばほら
if I sing them with you, look,
名曲になる
they'll become masterpieces.
友達以上が未満かより
Rather than whether we're more or less than friends,
名前のない特別な距離
it's a special distance without a name.
昨日の失敗も
Yesterday's failures,
明日の憂鬱も
and tomorrow's gloom,
君と話せば
if I talk with you,
笑い話になる
they'll become funny stories.
どこにいても
Wherever I am,
何をしてても
whatever I do,
声は飛んでいく 君の方向へ
my voice flies towards you.
どんより雨降りも
Gloomy rain,
しょんぼり泣き虫も
and being a sad crybaby,
君にかかればほら
look, when it's you,
キラキラ光る
they sparkle and shine.
嬉しい楽しいがもっと増えていく
Happiness and fun keep increasing even more,
無邪気な子供のように
like an innocent child.
抱きしめて
Hold me tight.
君に会いたい
I want to see you.
ということで後半戦になります！イエーイ！
So, we're heading into the second half! Yay!
これ挽回できるんですかー？
Can we actually make a comeback?
確かに。0ポイントなんですけど。
True. You have zero points, though.
0ポイントの方も多いですし、ちょっと現状ちょっとラスト1問になります！
There are many people with zero points, and currently, it's the last question!
ええー！？
What!?
終わりじゃん。
It's already over.
あたってもね... ぺこら1問しかあたってないけど、あたっても無理だよね...
Even if we get it... Pekora only got one right, so even if she gets this, it's impossible, right?
そうですね無理ですね。もう。
That's right, it's impossible. Already.
何で無理って言っちゃったの。ぺこら先輩はね...
Why did you say it's impossible? For Pekora-senpai...
でも団長はしご、え、でも団長はしごかけちゃおうかな...
But maybe Danchou will... well, maybe I'll throw you a lifeline...?
あ、はしごかける？
Oh, a lifeline?
まあまあちょっとそんなね、大丈夫ですよ！きっと！
Well, well, it's fine! Surely!
まあまあ。とりあえず、あのVTRをどうぞ！
Well, anyway. Please take a look at the VTR!
数日後
A few days later
さてさて、都内に戻ってきました。
Well, well, I'm back in Tokyo.
その後続々と必要な食材を全て集めたので、早速作っていきたいところなのですが...
I've since gathered all the necessary ingredients, so I'd like to start cooking right away, but...
まあ最高の食材があっても、この食材を使える最高の料理人がいないと、究極の牛丼にはならないよね。
Even with the best ingredients, without the best chef to use them, it won't be the ultimate gyudon.
ということで、神戸牛を扱わせたらこの人、という方をお呼びしました。どうぞ。
So, I've invited the person who's the best at handling Kobe beef. Come in.
こんにちは。
Hello.
今回料理を担当するのは...
Handling the cooking this time is...
神戸牛ダイア雷門西店料理長 佐々木康二さん。
Koji Sasaki, head chef of Kobe Beef DAIA Kaminarimon West store.
店舗グループ全体の年間総量約62万枚のステーキを焼き上げており、
He grills approximately 620,000 steaks annually across the entire restaurant group...
神戸牛の最も旨い食べ方を知り尽くした人物のひとりなのだ。
...and is one of the people who knows the most delicious ways to eat Kobe beef.
本日は佐々木料理長監修のもと、究極の牛丼を作っていきたいと思います。
Today, under Chef Sasaki's supervision, we will make the ultimate gyudon.
というわけで、究極の牛丼、調理開始。
And so, cooking the ultimate gyudon, start.
まずは玉ねぎを入れます。
First, add the onions.
淡路フルーツ玉ねぎ1個分を炒める
Fry one Awaji Fruit Onion
玉ねぎは低温でゆっくり火を通すことにより甘みがすごく出るので美味しくなります。
By cooking onions slowly at a low temperature, the sweetness comes out significantly, making them delicious.
玉ねぎを炒めたら、水と砂糖、みりんなどの調味料を鍋へ。
After frying the onions, add water, sugar, mirin, and other seasonings to the pot.
ひとふかしするまでゆっくり火を入れていきます。
Continue heating slowly until it comes to a boil.
それではお肉を入れていきます。
Now, add the meat.
で、ここでしっかりお肉をほぐしておいてください。
Now, make sure to break up the meat thoroughly here.
お肉に火が通りだしたらアクが出てくるので、アクは丁寧に取ってください。
As the meat cooks, scum will appear, so please remove it carefully.
このまま約10分ほど炊いていきます。
We will simmer it like this for about 10 minutes.
はい、楽しみです。
Okay, I'm looking forward to it.
煮込んでいる間にサーロインユッケ作りへ。
While it's simmering, let's move on to making sirloin yukke.
牛脂をフライパンにのせて、脂がしっかり出たらお肉をのせていきます。
Put beef fat in the pan, and once the oil is well out, add the meat.
念願のお肉... あー！
The long-awaited meat... Ah!
ここでお肉の旨みが逃げないように全体をよく焼いていきます。
To keep the meat's umami from escaping, sear the entire surface well.
それでは切っていきます。
Now, let's slice it.
ユッケダレと混ぜていきます。
Mix it with the yukke sauce.
料理長！高級なお肉がないときはどうすれば手軽に美味しい牛肉になるんでしょうか？
Chef! When we don't have expensive meat, how can we easily make beef delicious?
家庭でもよく食べる安いお肉でも美味しい牛肉にできる簡単な方法あったりしませんか？
Is there a simple way to make even the cheap meat we often eat at home delicious?
家庭でも美味しい柔らかいお肉を作るひと工夫として、ブライン液を作るといいかもしれません。
As a trick to make delicious, tender meat at home, it might be good to make a brine liquid.
なに〜？ブライン液？
What~? Brine liquid?
ということで最後のクエスチョンです。
And so, the final question.
ブライン液とは、水ととある調味料2つを組み合わせた液となります。
Brine liquid is a liquid made by combining water and two specific seasonings.
ブライン液を作るために水と合わせる2つの調味料とは？
What are the two seasonings mixed with water to make brine liquid?
二つの調味料を全て当ててください！
Guess both of the seasonings correctly!
何？最後に一発逆転？
What? A last-minute comeback?
超高得点ゲットのチャンスだよ！肉を柔らかくする...
It's a chance to get super high points! To make the meat tender...
みんなも頑張ってね！
Good luck, everyone!
動き、動き！イエーイ！
Movement, movement! Yay!
動きうるさいぺこ。ヒントとかないの、これ？ヒント、ヒント、ヒント！
Your movements are noisy, peko. Are there any hints for this? Hints, hints, hints!
逆転ボーナスチャンスということで、皆様、机の下をご覧ください！
As this is a Reversal Bonus Chance, everyone, please look under your desks!
何これ？え、何これ？ちょっと待って、これ...
What's this? Eh, what is it? Wait a second, this is...
何これ？人形がいる！何だろう？
What is this? There's a figure here! I wonder what it is?
はい、皆さん、YAGOOがいまーしたー！こちらのYAGOOをBETすることができまして...
Yes, everyone, it's YAGOO! You can bet this YAGOO figure, and...
BETすると何と...
...if you bet it, then remarkably...
10倍だ！
10倍です！
Ten times!
It's ten times!
えー！今までの何だったんだ
Ehh! What was all that effort for until now?
そうだ、最初から欲しかった。ズルだよこれ最初から欲しかった
Exactly, I wanted this from the start. That's a foul, I wanted it from the start.
1ポイントに10倍だから、それだけで、ぺこら先輩ですらも勝てるということで
Since it's 10x for 1 point, even Pekora-senpai can win with just that.
おー！食べれるぺこ。でもブライン液がわかんない...
Oh! I might be able to eat, peko. But I don't know what brine solution is...
わかんない... ブライン液... はい、ということで皆様、回答の記入、お願いいたします
I don't know... brine solution... Alright, everyone, please write down your answers.
え、これ問題、ヒントないの？これ
Wait, are there no hints for this question?
ノーヒント？ノーヒント？うそでしょ！
No hints? No hints? You've gotta be kidding!
欲しい欲しい、ヒント欲しい！
I want one, I want a hint!
まあ、料理をする人は知ってるかもしれないんですが、水100mlに対して...
Well, those who cook might know this, but per 100ml of water...
何々が5g...
...you add 5g of something...
5g...
5g? なるほどね。グラムってことはあれだよ、グラムだよ
5g? I see. If it's in grams, it's gotta be that.
グラム、グラム...
Grams, grams...
5g...?
皆さんの家に絶対ある
You definitely have it in your home.
全員ある、多分。自炊をするならば100%ありますよ
Everyone has it, probably. If you cook for yourself, you have it 100%.
グラム... 見たことないってことはない
Grams... It's impossible that you've never seen it.
だって液体だったらさっきみたいにmlっていうけど、そう、液体じゃない
Because if it were a liquid, you'd say ml like before. Right, it's not a liquid.
液体じゃない。グラム系のものね
It's not a liquid. It's something measured in grams.
あ〜もう大ヒント出しちゃったな
Ah, I gave away a huge hint.
え、絶対にある？本当？
ありますよ、絶対にありますよ
Eh, we definitely have it? Really?
You do, you definitely have it.
かなた、絶対みんなあるの、絶対みんなある？
Kanata, everyone definitely has it? Everyone?
絶対あるよ
え、待って、これちょっと書き始めて顔見よう
You definitely do.
Wait, let me start writing and then look at your face.
あははは、いやでもこれじゃない！
Ahahaha, no, it's not this!
これじゃない、これじゃねえぺこ
It's not this, it's not this, peko.
かなたちゃんぺこらのどう？
Kanata-chan, how's Pekora's?
かなたさん、みんなの家にはあるよね？
Kanata-san, it's in everyone's home, right?
もっと、もっとメジャーなもの。これみんなの家にある？
Something more... more major. Is this in everyone's home?
えっ、違う！かなた、私のも見て
Eh, no! Kanata, look at mine too.
もっとメジャーなやつ。これは？
A more major one. This is...?
あ〜、フレアもそれやばいぞ。まず食べられねえぞ
Ah, Flare, yours is bad too. First of all, it's inedible.
フレア頑張れ、いけるぞ
Good luck, Flare, you can do it.
あー！
Agh!
惜しい、惜しい！
So close, so close!
そこまで来たら答えは一つじゃないですか
If it's come to that, isn't there only one answer?
そろそろ時間か〜？うわ、ちょっと待って、えー
Is it almost time? Whoa, wait a second, uh...
あれ、団長は？え、ちょ？
Wait, what about Danchou? Eh, wait?
え、アイノエル食えないパターンあるかこれワンチャン
Wait, is there a chance Noel won't be able to eat?
え？アイノエル食えないパターンあるか、これワンチャン
Eh? Is there a chance Noel won't be able to eat?
はい、ということで皆さん、回答が出揃ってきましたということで
Alright, so everyone's answers are all in.
ではまた団長以外の3人の回答を一斉に表示していきましょう
Now then, let's reveal the answers of the three guests at once.
ドン！
Bam!
はい、何て書いてある？
Okay, what's written?
えーと、ぺこら先輩とマリン、ちょっとYAGOO邪魔だな
Let's see, Pekora-senpai and Marine... YAGOO is a bit in the way.
YAGOOの顔で、はい、塩、砂糖
Behind YAGOO's face... okay, salt and sugar.
そしてフレア先輩が塩、こしょう
And Flare-senpai put salt and pepper.
こしょうじゃない！そっか〜
それ間違えるわ〜
It's not pepper! I see...
I'd totally make that mistake.
いや〜分かれるかもしれませんよ。わかんないですけれども
Well, they might be divided. I don't know, though.
これでフレア合ってたらどうする？かなたが罠で...
What if Flare is right? What if Kanata's hint was a trap?
うわ〜罠の可能性もあるけど
Whoa, there's a possibility of a trap, but...
じゃあマリンどうしますか、BETしますか？
Well then, Marine, what will you do? Will you bet?
しますよ、当たり前っしょ！団員さーん！
I will, of course! Danii-san!
すみません団員さーん、出てきて
Excuse me, Danii-san, please come out.
全BETでいきますか？はい、出てきて、はい、きました
Going for an all-in bet? Yes, come out, okay, here they are.
じゃあ団員さんとYAGOO全BET、これでいきます
Then, all-in on Danii-san and YAGOO. I'll go with this.
これで当たってたら40ポイント貰えますからね
If you get it right, you'll get 40 points.
うわー！YAGOO一個落ちたぞ
Whoa! One YAGOO fell down.
なんかありました？今
なんか不吉だな、不吉だな
Did something just happen?
Something's ominous, very ominous.
不吉だな、並べてと
It's ominous. Let's line them up.
場所が嫌だな
I don't like the placement.
じゃあフレア先輩
Next, Flare-senpai.
賭けないと終わるので賭けます。復活狙いましょう
If I don't bet, it'll be over, so I'll bet. Let's aim for a comeback.
団員さんも呼んでおいてください
Please call Danii-san too.
可愛い。もしかしたら当たってるかもしれないから
Cute. Since there's a chance I'm right.
フレア先輩も全BETということで
Flare-senpai is also going all-in.
ぺこーらはYAGOO人形賭けまーす！
Pekora will bet her YAGOO figure!
みんなもBETしていきますね。YAGOOが揺れております
Everyone is betting. YAGOO is shaking.
それではですね、団長の答え見ていきましょうか
Now then, let's see Danchou's answer.
こちらです！はい！
Here it is! Bam!
砂糖と塩！
Sugar and salt!
Q. ブライン液を作るために水と合わせる2つの調味料とは？
Q. What are the two seasonings to combine with water to make brine solution?
これは自信がありますよ
I'm confident in this one.
やっぱり、こう... なんて言うんですかね、甘いのとしょっぱいので無限ループということで、はい、こちら！
Because, well, how should I put it... sweet and salty makes for an infinite loop, so here it is!
おねがいしまーす！
Here we go!
最終問題ですのでね。
Since it's the final question.
それでは、この中に正解はいるのでしょうか？
Now, will we find the correct answer among these?
正解を発表いたします。正解はこちら！
Time to announce the correct answer. The answer is... this!
答え：水100mlに対して、砂糖5g・塩5gでございます！
Answer: 5g of sugar and 5g of salt for 100ml of water!
大丈夫、みんなで1枚ずつ分けてあげるから
It's okay, we'll all share one bowl each.
これがね、ブライ液ということで...
This is what they call 'brine'...
塩と砂糖でございました〜！
It was salt and sugar!
確かにこれなら全部の家庭にあるね、絶対にね
That's true, every household definitely has those.
ということでね、こちらの結果についてはVTRの後にちょっと振り返っていきたいと思いますので...
So, we'll look back at these results after the video...
それでは、VTRの続きスタート！
And now, let's start the rest of the video!
究極牛丼の完成に向けて、残りは盛り付けのみ。しかしその前に...
With the ultimate beef bowl nearing completion, only the plating remains. But before that...
料理長、団長は玉ねぎのシャキシャキ感めっちゃ好きなんですよね
Chef, I really love the crunchy texture of onions.
それでは、ノエルさんが持ってきたフンドーキンの醤油を使ってひと工夫していきましょう
Then, let's add a special touch using the Fundokin soy sauce that Noel brought.
この醤油は... 団長のマイ・フェイバリット醤油！
This soy sauce is... my favorite soy sauce!
玉ねぎとフンドーキン醤油を和えます。
Mix the onions with Fundokin soy sauce.
普通の醤油より甘いんですよね。
It's sweeter than normal soy sauce.
それでは盛り付けていきます。
Now, let's plate it.
多めでお願いします！
A lot of it, please!
分かりました (笑)
Understood (laughs).
淡路玉ねぎフンドーキン醤油和えを乗せていきます。
Top it with Awaji onions mixed with Fundokin soy sauce.
神戸牛の炙り肉を置いていきます。
Place the seared Kobe beef on top.
うわー、美味しそう！
Wow, looks delicious!
最後に薬味のネギを散らしていきます。
Finally, sprinkle some green onions as a garnish.
完成でございます。
It's complete.
究極の牛丼、完成！
The ultimate beef bowl is complete!
なんと美しいのでしょうか。
How beautiful it is.
スタジオのみんなはどれだけ正解できたかな？
How many did everyone in the studio get right?
それではお待ちかねの実食タイム！
Now, for the long-awaited tasting time!
ということでですね、正解は団長、ペコら先輩、マリン...
And so, Noel, Pekora, and Marin were correct...
不正解はフレア先輩...
And Flare was incorrect...
冷静に考えたらウチ、コショウねぇや！
Looking at it calmly, I don't even have pepper!
はい、皆様のですね、ポイントの方も発表していきましょうか。
Alright, let's announce everyone's points.
最終的にはフレア先輩、0ポイントになっております！
In the end, Flare is at 0 points!
続いてペコら先輩、11ポイント！
Next, Pekora with 11 points!
そしてノエル団長が20ポイント！
And Captain Noel with 20 points!
そして、なんとマリンが40ポイント！ 優勝！
And Marin has 40 points! The winner!
貯めておいてよかった〜。最後まで温存しておいてよかった。
I'm glad I saved them up. Glad I held onto them until the end.
残念ながらフレア先輩だけ食べられ... ま... せん！
Unfortunately, only Flare won't be able to eat... not!
いや、悲しいよ... いいよ、しょうがねぇ...
No, it's so sad... It's okay, can't be helped...
待って！
Wait!
あ、この...
Oh, this...
団長、10ポイントあげる！
I'll give you 10 points!
団長の20ポイント中の10ポイントで...
With 10 of Noel's 20 points...
そんなことがいいんですか？
Is that allowed?
これで全員もしかして食べられるということに？ いいみたいですよ！
Does this mean everyone can eat? It seems so!
あったけぇ世界だー！
What a warm world!
じゃあ皆で食べていきましょうか！
Then let's all eat together!
食べましょー！ 究極牛丼！
Let's eat! The ultimate beef bowl!
めっちゃいい匂いしてる！
It smells amazing!
いいですか？ 食べても。
Is it okay if we eat?
それでは、いただきます！
In that case, let's eat!
なんていい番組なんだ...
What a great show...
いいなんだよ、皆で食べたら究極よ。
It's fine, it's ultimate when we eat together.
うま！ めちゃめちゃ美味しい。
Yum! This is delicious.
えっ、甘！
Oh, it's sweet!
あんま！ 玉ねぎ！
So sweet! The onions!
究極かもしれん。今まで食べた中で一番美味しい。
This might be the ultimate. Best I've ever had.
うん、めっちゃうまい。一番美味しいな。
Yeah, it's so good. The best ever.
玉ねぎがこんなに美味しいなんて。お肉もっうま。
I can't believe onions are this good. The meat is yummy too.
めちゃ旨い。これ毎日食べたい。
It's so good. I want to eat this every day.
あらっ、もしかして... ぺこらっちさ、毎日牛丼が食べたい？
Oh, maybe... Pekora, do you want to eat beef bowl every day?
ちょっといいですか？ 皆さんが食べてる間に...
Could I have a moment? While everyone is eating...
ということで、団長ちょっと重大告知ありまーす！
So, I have a major announcement to make!
まあ、ホロライブ入ってからずっと牛丼が好きって言ってたんですけど...
Well, ever since I joined Hololive, I've been saying I love gyudon...
なんと！
And now!
まさか！
No way!
この度...
This time...
おお！まさか！？
Oh! Could it be!?
牛丼の...
A song...
曲を作りました！
...about gyudon!
おおー！
Whoa!
やだって、やだって話来ないもーん。
Because, well, nobody was asking me to make one.
ということでね、自分で自主的に曲を作ったので、あの、聞いてもらってもいいですか？
So, I went ahead and made a song on my own. Would you like to hear it?
食べながらでいいんで。
You can listen while you eat.
食べながら聞くの！？
While eating!?
はい！それでは、聞いてください！
Yes! Now then, please listen!
「ぎゅーどんかーにばる！」
'Gyudon Carnival!'
イェーイ！
Yay!
ギュッ！ドン！ギュードン・ドン！ギュッ！
Gyu! Don! Gyudon-don! Gyu!
ギュッ！ドン！ギュードン・ドン！ギュッ！♡
Gyu! Don! Gyudon-don! Gyu! ♡
ギュッ！ドン！ギュードン・ドン！ギュッ！
Gyu! Don! Gyudon-don! Gyu!
ギュッ！ドン！ギュッとしてドーン！
Gyu! Don! Squeeze and boom!
ぎゅーどんかーにばる！
Gyudon Carnival!
作詞・作曲・編曲：まろん (IOSYS)
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Maron (IOSYS)
せーの、ギュッドン！
Ready, go, Gyudon!
大好き！ギュッとしてドーン！
I love it! Squeeze and boom!
オロポンかけてさっぱりとハピハピ (ハピハピ)
Add grated radish ponzu for a refreshing happy-happy (happy-happy)
豪華に特盛り！わーい！(ギュードンかーにばる！)
A luxurious extra-large serving! Yay! (Gyudon Carnival!)
チーズや温玉トッピングはお好み (おいしー！)
Toppings like cheese or soft-boiled egg as you like (delicious!)
どれも最高！笑顔で決めたろう
Everything's great! Let's decide with a smile
はぁ～い、腹ペコのパブちゃんたち～ こっちでちゅよ～
Hey there, my hungry little ones~ Over here~
食べる前には、お姉さんと運動しよーね～
Before we eat, let's exercise with big sister~
1, 2, Let's Go!!
Hey Come On!! Everybody Standup!!
Are Yoo Hungry!? (O-YEAH!!)
ギュッギュッギュッギュッ ギュッギュッギュッギュッ
Gyu-gyu-gyu-gyu Gyu-gyu-gyu-gyu
からの～ いただきましゅる～！
And now... let's eat!
さあさあ牛丼だ！ 牛丼だ！
Come on, it's gyudon! It's gyudon!
一緒に食べよう
Let's eat together
キミと仲良くカーニバル
A friendly carnival with you
トロトロちゅわわぁ (1, 2, どーん！)
Melty and gooey (1, 2, boom!)
ほろりお肉 お肉
Tender meat, meat
不満じゃだめっ
No being grumpy
全部食べたら褒めちゃう
If you eat it all, I'll praise you
なでなでよしよしちゅっちゅっちゅっ
Pet-pet, there-there, kiss-kiss-kiss
あびゃー！
Abya!
せーの、ギュッドン！
Ready, go, Gyudon!
わぁ～～～～～！
Waaaaa!
えっ、牛丼が嫌い…？
Eh, you hate gyudon...?
もう、なんでそういうこと言うの！
Jeez, why would you say such a thing!
そんな悪い子は～
A naughty child like that...
食べちゃうぞ♡
...I'll eat you up! ♡
アビャアビャビャ...
Abya abyabya...
すきー！しゅきしゅきだいしゅきー！
I love it! I love-love-love it!
らう゛ぃー！らう゛らう゛洗脳中～♡
Lovey! Love-love brainwashing in progress~ ♡
むっちー！むちむち責めちゃダメ～
Gooey! No being too hard on me~
よく出来ました！ほっぺにちゅ～！
Well done! A kiss on the cheek!
全く、まだ足りないの…？
Jeez, you still haven't had enough...?
それでも全然足りません
Even so, it's not enough at all
まだまだ、全然足りないの
Still, it's not enough at all
ドキがムネムネ止まらな～い！
My heart won't stop pounding!
牛丼を食べるときは、お口でふーふーして…って、
When you eat gyudon, blow on it with your mouth... wait,
あっ、いきなりがっついちゃって、かわいい～
Ah, you're scarfing it down already, so cute~
優しく…丁寧に、だぞ？
Be gentle... and careful, okay?
あははっ…いい子いい子
Ahaha... good boy, good boy
お腹、いっぱいになっちゃったね。
You're full now, aren't you?
一緒に、寝ちゃう…？♡
Shall we... sleep together? ♡
おやすみなさーい♪
Good night~ ♪
もしもキミが シュンとしちゃっても
Even if you're feeling down
ぎゅってぎゅってぎゅって 抱きしめたげる
I'll hold you tight, tight, tight
ほら、おいで～～！
Here, come here~~!
さあさあ牛丼だ！ 牛丼だ！
Come on, it's gyudon! It's gyudon!
一緒に食べよう
Let's eat together
キミと何度でもカーニバル
A carnival with you again and again
トロトロちゅわわぁ (1, 2, どーん！)
Melty and gooey (1, 2, boom!)
ほろりお肉 お肉
Tender meat, meat
不満じゃだめっ
No being grumpy
全部食べたら褒めちゃう
If you eat it all, I'll praise you
なでなでよしよしちゅっちゅっちゅっ
Pet-pet, there-there, kiss-kiss-kiss
あびゃー！
Abya!
せーの、ギュッドン！
Ready, go, Gyudon!
大好き！ギュッとしてドーン！
I love it! Squeeze and boom!
まだまだドーン！
Still more boom!
白銀ノエルの牛丼ドーン！
Shirogane Noel's Gyudon Boom!
ギュッ！
Gyu!
はーい、いかがでしたでしょうか、新曲！
So, how was it? My new song!
可愛かったー！最高でしたー！
It was so cute! It was the best!
自由な体制で見てんなよ！
Looking in such a free posture!
いや、これには意味があるんだって。ノエル、やっちゃって。
No, there's a meaning to this. Noel, go ahead.
あ、そうですね。あ、じゃあ、ちょっと、あの、正座... あー、あー！
Ah, right. Then, I'll sit... Ah!
中からもありがとうございます！
Thank you from the inside too!
ではでは、ちょっと、さらにね、告知が続きますということで。
Now then, there's more announcements to follow.
皆様、おくつろぎながら見てくれると嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you all watch while relaxing.
ということで、今年も、あります、こちら。ドン！
So, this year too, we have this. Boom!
白銀ノエル生誕記念グッズ！
Shirogane Noel Birthday Celebration Goods!
おー！
Yay!
私も、私もおぎゃってるぞ！
I'm, I'm "ogya-ing" too!
そうでしょ。夏は大自然でございます。
Right? Summer is all about nature.
では、詳細見ていきましょう。えー、最初は、こちら！
Let's look at the details. First, this!
あの、先ほどのイラストを使った、あの、Nardack先生描き下ろしのポストカードフレームになります！
This is a postcard frame featuring the illustration from earlier, drawn by Nardack-sensei!
おー！
Oh!
いいでしょ。やっぱね、結構さ、我々いろいろね、サイン入りのポストカードとか結構書きますんで、
Nice, right? We often write signed postcards and such,
そういうの、なんか入れ込めるといいなと思って。
so I thought it'd be nice to have something to put them in.
あと、こういうのなんか作ったことなかったなということで、ちょっと、作ってみました。
And since I'd never made anything like this, I decided to try.
ぺこちゃん！ぺこちゃん！もうちょい、さ、こっちに来て、いいの？
Peko-chan! Peko-chan! Come a bit more this way, okay?
半分だけでいいの？
Is half enough?
いいの。あー、そうかも。いいけどね。
It's fine. Ah, maybe. It's okay though.
なんかフリーダムだね。
Quite free-spirited, huh.
ということで、はい、じゃあ、次いきましょう。次！
So, okay, let's move on to the next one. Next!
で、こちらが、結構ね、団長的に、あの、すごい、試みなんですけど。
And this is a big challenge for me personally...
こちら、白銀ノエル 1stアルバム『のえさんぽ』出ます！
Shirogane Noel's 1st Album "Noe Sanpo" is coming out!
おー！のえさんぽ！イエーイ！ナイス1stアルバム！
Oh! Noe Sanpo! Yay! Nice 1st album!
そうなんですよ。いや、本当ありがとうございます。
That's right. No, really, thank you.
えーっと、このイラストはですね、あの、楠木はるい先生描き下ろし。
This illustration was drawn by Kusunoki Harui-sensei.
そして、あの、まあ、この、デザインなんですけど、あの、saku39さんのデザインになっております！
And the design is by saku39-san!
そしてね、なんと特典に、アナザージャケットカードがありますので、
And what's more, there's an another jacket card as a bonus.
いや、ちょっと、歌頑張ったんで、ぜひぜひ、皆さん聴いてください。
I really worked hard on the singing, so please give it a listen.
こちら、ぜひ聴いて、凄、頑張って、ありがとうね。
Please listen to this, I worked really hard.
頑張ったね。ありがとう。
You worked hard. Thank you.
じゃあ、次。はい、こちら！『おさんぽノエルぬいぐるみ ディアンドル衣装ver.』ということで。
Next. Here! "Osanpo Noel Plushie Dirndl Outfit ver."
かわいいー！
So cute!
そうなんですよ。やっぱ、牛さんがね、ちょっと今回も、テーマになってる...
That's right. After all, cows are the theme again this time...
あ、YAGOO、それYAGOOになっちゃうんだけど、牛さん。
Ah, YAGOO, that's becoming YAGOO, but the cow...
この、牛さんで、やっぱ、『のえさんぽ』の曲を聴きながら、これ、携えて、
I hope you can carry it around while listening to "Noe Sanpo"...
こうやって、一緒に行けたらなと、思っておりますので、持ち歩いてください。
and go places together, so please take it with you.
あ、すごいツノが生えてる。
Oh, it has amazing horns.
牛、YAGOOみたい、YAGOOっぽいんだよな。
It looks like YAGOO, it's very YAGOO-like.
じゃあ、はい、次いきましょう。で、こちら。『一緒に、おさんぽ♡リバーシブルバケットハット』ということで。
Next. "Osanpo Together♡ Reversible Bucket Hat."
そうなんです、おしゃれだし、さっきの、キービジュアルの方にも、実は、被ってたんですよ、団長。
It's stylish, and I was actually wearing it in the key visual.
おそろっちのね、あの、リバーシブルバケットハットなので、
It's a matching reversible bucket hat...
まあ、ちょっと、牛さん柄ちょっと恥ずかしいなって人は、まあ、黒の方をメインにして、
so if the cow pattern is a bit much, you can use the black side...
ちょっと、ね、牛さん柄はアクセントに使ったりとか。
and use the cow pattern as an accent.
チラ見えがね、おしゃれ。いいじゃんよ。
The peek-a-boo effect is stylish. It's good.
でも、まあ、白銀ノエル大好きって人はね、『NOEL』というロゴがついた、こっち側を、
For those who love Shirogane Noel, you can use the side with the logo.
ピョッてね、被っていただければと、思います。お、リングも付いてる。
Just wear it like this. Oh, it even has a ring.
はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you.
では、次、ポン！ということで、えーっと、誕生日記念フルセットということで！
Now, next, boom! The Birthday Celebration Full Set!
今回ね、あの、なんと、このセットを、全部買ってくださった方に、あの、特典！
For those who buy the complete set, there's a bonus!
団長書きます、白銀ノエル直筆サイン、箔押し、メッセージ入りのね、あの、ポストカード、
I'll write handwritten signatures, foil-stamped messages on postcards!
やらせていただきましょう！
Yes, I'll be doing that!
わーい！
Yay!
やばい、ちょっとね、無制限なので、ちょっと、頑張りますので、
It's unlimited, so I'll do my best.
あの、なんか、前回戦争でちょっとね、買えなかった人もいたので。
Some people couldn't buy it last time due to the sell-out...
誕生日はちょっとみんなにハッピーになってもらいたいので、団長頑張って書きます。
so I want everyone to be happy on my birthday.
団長頑張って書きます。お耳ね。
I'll work hard on writing them. The ears, right.
で、もう一つは、お誕生日お礼ボイスもありますので、
And there's also a birthday thank-you voice.
そちらも聴いてください。ということで、ぜひチェックしてください！
Please listen to that as well. Please check it out!
わーい！
Yay!
はい、いや、みんな、ありがとうね、お付き合いいただきまして。
Yes, well, everyone, thank you for sticking with me.
いえいえ、楽しかったし、美味しかったし、ありがとうございます。
No problem, it was fun and delicious, thank you.
いえいえ、いえいえ。なんか、本当にね、やっぱ、ご飯は、みんなで食べたほうが美味しいので。
No, no. Food tastes better when you eat it together.
やっぱこう、大好きな3期生と、そしてね、司会と...
With my beloved 3rd generation members, and the host...
今、何をしよ... あ、何でもない。あ、本当。まあ、大好きなね。
What were you doing just now? Ah, nothing. Well, the ones I love.
あ、今、大好きって言っちゃった。あ、お互い、大好き。
Ah, I said "love" just now. We love each other.
司会は、やっぱ、かなたんということで、ありがとうございます。
And thank you to the host, Kanatan.
大好き。みんな大好き。本当にありがとう。最高の誕生日になりました。
We love you. Love you all. Really, thank you. This has been the best birthday.
おめでとう！ありがとうね！
Congratulations! Thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
それじゃあ、『牛丼カーニバル』も聴いてね。
And then, please listen to "Gyudon Carnival" too.
はい、ということで、みんなありがとう！バイバーイ！
Yes, so, thank you everyone! Bye-bye!
おつまするー！
Otsumasuru!
おつまするー！バイバーイ！おめでとう！ありがとう！
Otsumasuru! Bye-bye! Congratulations! Thank you!
白銀ノエル、待望のファーストアルバム『のえさんぽ』
Shirogane Noel's long-awaited first album, "Noe-san Po",
11月25日に発売したよ！
was released on November 25th!
全10曲、今の団長をぎゅーっと詰め込んだアルバムになっています！
It's an album with 10 songs, packed with the current Danchou!
いっぱいきいてほしいな♥
I hope you listen to it a lot ♥